Guide to the Arthur E. Scott photograph collection, 1910-1976
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Arthur E. Scott photograph collection
1910-1976
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Arthur E. Scott, 1917-1976
C0096
32 linear ft.; 43 boxes; 27 scrapbooks
This collection contains photographs taken by Arthur E. Scott, a photojournalist and photo-historian for the U.S. Senate. It contains over 5,000 prints and negatives of United States politicians (mainly Senators), political events such as campaigns and inaugurations, and landmarks throughout the Washington, D.C. area, from the mid-1930s to the 1970s. There are also 27 scrapbooks compiled by Arthur E. Scott, primarily consisting of newspaper clippings of Scott's photographs. The collection also contains glass negatives from the 1910s and 1920s that were taken by other photographers.
Administrative Information
Alternative Form Available
Sample images from the Scott collection are available online through the Arthur E. Scott Photograph Collection.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Grace L. Scott in 1981. Scrapbooks donated by Barbara Thaler in 2006.
Biographical Information
Arthur E. "Scotty" Scott, was born March 14, 1917, in Montpelier, Vermont. In 1925 his family moved to Washington, D.C., where Scott spent most of his life. Scott began his press career at the age of 13, as a copyboy for the Washington Times-Herald. From 1934-1955, Scott served as a news photographer for International News Photos (INP) and Wide World Photos. Scott first covered the United States Congress in 1935 as a photographer for the Washington Times From 1955-1974, Scott worked as a photographer for the Republican Senatorial Committee (1965-1964) and the Republication Policy Committee (1964-1974). In 1975, the year the Senate Historical Office was created, Scott became the Senate's first photo-historian. As photo-historian, Scott was tasked with building a collection of graphic representations of the Senate's history. Scott died on December 2, 1976.
Scope and Content
This collection contains photographs taken by Arthur E. Scott, a photojournalist and photo-historian for the U.S. Senate. It contains over 5,000 prints and negatives of United States politicians (mainly Senators), political events such as campaigns and inaugurations, and landmarks throughout the Washington, D.C. area, from the mid-1930s to the 1970s. There are also 27 scrapbooks compiled by Arthur E. Scott, primarily consisting of newspaper clippings of Scott's photographs. The collection also contains photographs from the 1910s and 1920s that were taken by other photographers. The collection contains prints and film negatives in various sizes, as well as glass plate negatives. Boxes 1 through 11, 29, 30, and 43 contain photographic prints; boxes 12 through 25 contain 4 x 5 inch negatives; boxes 26 and 27 contain 4 x 5 inch glass plate negatives; and boxes 31 through 42 contain slides, 35mm negatives, and negatives of various other sizes. The majority of the photographs are in black and white unless otherwise noted.
Series 1 contains photographs of people, including Senators, Representatives, Vice Presidents, Presidents, Supreme Court Justices, and other politicians. It also contains photographs of celebrities, politicians' families, and others. This series contains individual as well as group shots. This series includes photographs of many Republican Party Senators, including George D. Aiken, Gordon Allott, Clifford P. Case, Norris Cotton, Everett M. Dirksen, Robert J. Dole, Hiram Fong, Barry M. Goldwater, Roman L. Hruska, Mike Mansfield, Charles H. Percy, Hugh Scott, Margaret Chase Smith, John G. Tower, and many others. Presidents and Vice Presidents pictured include Calvin Coolidge, Dwight D. Eisenhower, John N. Garner, Herbert C. Hoover, Gerald R. Ford, Lyndon B. Johnson, and Richard M. Nixon. The series also includes photographs of astronauts John Glenn, Virgil "Gus" Grissom, and Alan B. Shepard.
Series 2 contains photographs of building interiors and exteriors, monuments, landmarks, and parks. The majority of the series consists of photographs of the Washington, D.C. area. This series includes photographs of Arlington National Cemetery, the U.S. Capitol Building, the U.S. Supreme Court Building, the Potomac River, the Washington Monument, and the Lincoln Memorial. It also includes aerial shots of Washington, D.C. and the Panama Canal Zone, Panama.
Series 3 contains photographs of events such as dinners, meetings, fundraisers, campaigns, conventions, and inaugurations. The events pictured in the series include the 1960 and 1964 Republican National Conventions; Richard M. Nixon campaign events in California and Hawaii (1960); and inaugurations and oaths of office for politicians such as Gerald R. Ford, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Richard M. Nixon, Nelson A. Rockefeller, and Warren G. Harding. It also contains photographs of natural disasters, such as floods, and photographs of politicians and celebrities receiving Buddy Poppies from the Veterans of Foreign Wars.
Series 4 contains photographs of published newspapers, as well as photographs of art works. It also contains reference publications and correspondence which relate to the photographs in the collection. Photographs of published newspapers include New York Times and New York Herald articles on the Battle of Gettysburg and the deaths of Abraham Lincoln and Theodore Roosevelt. The art works pictured included the George Gordon Meade Memorial, Samuel Gompers Memorial, and a monument to Casimir Pulaski. The series also includes "Virginia Political Greats", a report written by Scott in May 1976, as well as correspondence and captions regarding photographs taken by Scott.
Series 5 consists of scrapbooks compiled by Arthur Scott. These scrapbooks document events from 1918 through 1946. Most items contained within the scrapbooks are newspaper clippings, many of which depict photographs taken by Scott. The scrapbooks document events including the presidencies of Franklin D. Roosevelt and Harry S. Truman, as well as the run-up to World War II and homefront activities during the war years. The scrapbooks also contain press passes, expense reports, and schedules relating to Scott's photojournalism activities.
Series 6 consists of photographic supplies used by Scott. Photographic supplies include slide cases, as well as film canisters labeled "1952", "1964 GOP Convention San Francisco", "Gene Autry by Barry Goldwater", and "Stereo Photos South America Vacation 1966".
Arrangement
Organized into six series.
Series 1: People, 1910-1976 (Boxes 1-7, 12-22, 26-27, 29-42)
Series 2: Places, 1927-1976 (Boxes 7-9, 22-23, 27, 31, 43, Oversize)
Series 3: Events, 1921-1976 (Boxes 9-11, 23-25, 27, 30, 33, 35-36, 38-42)
Series 4: Art, Publications, Reference Materials, 1918-1976 (Boxes 11, 25, 27, 35, 38)
Series 5: Scrapbooks, 1918-1946 (Volumes 1-14 and unnumbered)
Series 6: Realia, 1950s-1960s (Box 28)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives holds many other photograph collections. The Charles Baptie photograph collection contains many similar subjects, as does the Oliver F. Atkins photograph collection.
The Senate Historical Office holds the Arthur E. Scott Collection.
Index Terms
Persons:
Aiken, George D. (George David), 1892-1984--Photographs.; Allott, Gordon, 1907-1989--Photographs.; Ashurst, Henry Fountain, 1874-1962--Photographs.; Barkley, Alben William, 1877-1956--Photographs.; Beall, J. Glenn (John Glenn), 1927-2006--Photographs.; Bennett, Wallace F. (Wallace Foster), 1898-1993--Photographs.; Bible, Alan, 1909-1988--Photographs.; Boggs, James Caleb, 1909-1993--Photographs.; Borah, William Edgar, 1865-1940--Photographs.; Bridges, Styles, 1898-1961--Photographs.; Bush, Prescott Sheldon, 1895-1972--Photographs.; Case, Clifford P. (Clifford Philip), 1904-1982--Photographs.; Cochran, Steve, 1917-1965--Photographs.; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933--Photographs.; Cooper, John Sherman, 1901-1991--Photographs.; Cotton, Norris, 1900- --Photographs.; Curtis, Carl T. (Carl Thomas), 1905-2000--Photographs.; Dern, George Henry, 1872-1936--Photographs.; Dirksen, Everett McKinley--Photographs.; Dole, Robert J., 1923- --Photographs.; Dominick, Peter H. (Peter Hoyt), 1915-1981--Photographs.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969--Photographs.; Elizabeth II, Queen of Great Britain, 1926- --Photographs.; Fannin, Paul J. (Paul Jones), 1907-2002--Photographs.; Fong, Hiram, 1907-2004--Photographs.; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006--Photographs.; Garner, John Nance, 1868-1967--Photographs.; Glenn, John, 1921- --Photographs.; Goldwater, Barry M. (Barry Morris), 1909-1998--Photographs.; Griffin, Robert P. (Robert Paul), 1923- --Photographs.; Grissom, Virgil I.--Photographs.; Hansen, Clifford P. (Clifford Peter), 1912-2009--Photographs.; Harrison, Pat, 1881-1941--Photographs.; Hickenlooper, Bourke B. (Bourke Blakemore), 1896-1971--Photographs.; Holt, Rush Dew, 1905-1955--Photographs.; Hoover, Herbert Charles, 1903-1969--Photographs.; Hruska, Roman L. (Roman Lee), 1904-1999--Photographs.; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986--Photographs.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973--Photographs.; Jordan, Len B. (Len Beck), 1899-1983--Photographs.; Keating, Kenneth B. (Kenneth Barnard), 1900-1975--Photographs.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963--Photographs.; Kuchel, Thomas H.--Photographs.; Mansfield, Mike, 1903-2001--Photographs.; Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959--Photographs.; McNary, Charles Linza, 1874-1944--Photographs.; Morton, Thruston B. (Thruston Ballard), 1907-1982--Photographs.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994--Photographs.; Pepper, Claude, 1900-1989--Photographs.; Percy, Charles H., 1919- --Photographs.; Pittman, Key, 1872-1940--Photographs.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979--Photographs.; Schoeppel, Andrew Frank, 1894-1962--Photographs.; Scott, Hugh, 1900-1994--Photographs.; Scott, William Lloyd, 1915-1997--Photographs.; Shepard, Alan B. (Alan Bartlett), 1923-1998--Photographs.; Smith, Margaret Chase, 1897-1995--Photographs.; Thurmond, Strom, 1902-2003--Photographs.; Tower, John G. (John Goodwin), 1925-1991--Photographs.; Tydings, Millard E. (Millard Evelyn), 1890-1961--Photographs.; Valeo, Francis R. (Francis Ralph), 1916-2006--Photographs.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951--Photographs.; Wiley, Alexander, 1884-1967--Photographs.; Woodring, Harry Hines, 1887-1967--Photographs.
Corporate Names:
Arlington National Cemetery (Arlington, Va.)--Photographs.; Boy Scouts of America--Photographs.; Supreme Court Building (Washington, D.C.)--Photographs.; United States. Supreme Court--Officials and employees--Photographs.; United States Capitol (Washington, D.C.)--Photographs.; United States. Congress. House.--Photographs.; United States. Congress. Senate.--Photographs.; Washington National Cathedral (Washington, D.C.)--Photographs.
Geographical Names:
Washington (D.C.)--Photographs.; Panama Canal (Panama)--Photographs.; Potomac River--Photographs.
Subjects:
Astronauts--Photographs.; Actors--Photographs.; Campaign speeches--Photographs.; Committees--Photographs.; Congresses and conventions--Photographs.; Eating and drinking--Photographs.; Funeral rites and ceremonies--Photographs.; Legislators--United States--Photographs.; Legislators' spouses--Photographs.; Lincoln Memorial (Washington, D.C.)--Photographs.; National Statuary Hall (United States Capitol, Washington, D.C.)--Photographs.; Oaths--Washington, D.C.--1970s--Photographs.; Political campaigns--Photographs.; Political conventions--Photographs.; Presidents--United States--Inauguration--Photographs.; Presidents--United States--Photographs.; Speeches, addresses, etc.--Photographs.; Tomb of the Unknowns (Va.)--Photographs.; Vice-Presidents--United States--Photographs.; Washington Monument (Washington, D.C.)--Photographs.
Document Types:
Photographic prints.; Portraits.; Negatives.; Slides.; Aerial photographs.; Group portraits.
Contents List
- Series 1: People, 1910-1976; (Boxes 1-7, 12-22, 26-27, 29-42)
  Series 1 contains photographs of people, including Senators, Representatives, Vice Presidents, Presidents, Supreme Court Justices, and other politicians. It also contains photographs of celebrities, politicians' families, and others. This series contains individual as well as group shots. This series is divided into the following subseries:
  - Subseries 1.1: Senators, 1930-1976
    Subseries 1.1 contains photographs of Senators. The majority of Senators pictured are members of the Republican Party. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by name and then chronologically within each name.
    - Aiken, George D., 1970s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - All Senators, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Includes Peter H. Dominick, Paul J. Fannin, Hubert H. Humphrey, Jr., George D. Aiken, Hiram L. Fong; (1 of 8)
    - All Senators, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Includes Margaret Chase Smith, Hugh D. Scott, Peter H. Dominick, George D. Aiken, Hiram L. Fong, Everett M. Dirksen, Margaret Chase Smith, Edward M. Kennedy, Norris H. Cotton; (2 of 8)
    - All Senators, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Includes Jacob K. Javits, Lyndon B. Johnson, Hiram L. Fong, George D. Aiken, Michael Mansfield; (3 of 8)
    - All Senators, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes Hubert H. Humphrey, Everett M. Dirksen, Edward M. Kennedy, Margaret Chase Smith; (4 of 8)
    - All Senators, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Includes Paul J. Fannin, George D. Aiken, J. William Fulbright;(5 of 8)
    - All Senators, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Includes Norris H. Cotton, Hiram L. Fong, Jacob K. Javits, Abraham A. Ribicoff, Hubert H. Humphrey, Margaret Chase Smith, Lyndon B. Johnson, Robert F. Kennedy; Mike Mansfield; (6 of 8)
    - All Senators, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Peter H. Dominick; Paul J. Fannin; Everett M. Dirksen, Hiram L. Fong, Hugh D. Scott, William Proxmire, Joseph S. Clark; (7 of 8)
    - All Senators, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Includes John G. Tower, Jacob K. Javits, Mike Mansfield, Margaret Chase Smith, George D. Aiken, Leverett Saltonstall; Everett M. Dirksen, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Hugh D. Scott, Hiram L. Fong; (8 of 8)
    - Appropriations Board and other Senators, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Includes Hiram L. Fong, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Hubert H. Humphrey, Jacob K. Javits, Margaret Chase Smith, John G. Tower, Hugh D. Scott, Lyndon B. Johnson, Leverett Saltonstall, George D. Aiken, Barry M. Goldwater, Richard M. Nixon, Jack R. Miller; (1 of 2)
    - Appropriations Board and other Senators, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Includes Margaret Chase Smith, Peter H. Dominick, Hugh D. Scott, Hubert H. Humphrey, Jacob K. Javits, Barry M. Goldwater, Richard M. Nixon, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Paul J. Fannin, George D. Aiken, Everett M. Dirksen, Robert F. Kennedy; (2 of 2)
    - Ashurst, Henry F., 1930s-1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Austin, Warren R., 1933-1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Baker, Howard H., Jr., 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Beall, John G., Jr., 1970s (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Portrait
    - Buckley, James L., July 25, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Case, Clifford P., 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Sketch portrait
    - Cotton, Norris H., 1970s (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Connally, Thomas T. (Tom), 1950s (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Showing model for the east front extension of the U.S. Capitol building to Warren Austin, Harry S. Truman, Charles Andrews, and David Lynn
    - Copied prints of 19th century senators, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Henry Wilson, Lyman Trumbull, John Sherman, Charles Sumner, Hiram Rhodes Revels, Edmund G. Ross, Charles W. Jones, George C. Perkins, Schuyler Colfax, Abijah Gilbert, Hannibal Hamlin, Justin S. Morrill
    - Caraway, Hattie Wyatt, 1931-1945 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Curtis, Carl T., 1970s (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Includes color portrait
    - Democratic Senators, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Includes Carey E. Kefauver, Stuart Symington, Robert C. Byrd, Kenneth B. Keating, John Stennis
    - Dirksen, Everett M., 1951-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Davis, James J., 1930-1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Dole, Robert J., 1970s (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ellender, Allen J., 1940s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Fannin, Paul J., 1970s (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Fong, Hiram L., 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Includes Ellyn Fong
    - Goldwater, Barry M., 1970s (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Includes color photographs
    - Griffin, Robert P., 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Hansen, Clifford P., 1970s (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Includes Martha Hansen, color photographs
    - Harrison, Byron P., 1930s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hatch, Carl A., 1933-1949 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hruska, Roman L., 1954-1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Javits, Jacob K., 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Kennedy, Edward M. (Ted), 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Kennedy, John F., 1953-1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Kennedy, Robert F., 1960s (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - King, William H., 1930s (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - La Follette, Robert M., Jr., 1930s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Laxalt, Paul D., 1970s (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1937-1952 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Mansfield, Michael J. (Mike), 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Mathias, Charles M., Jr., 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Includes color photograph
    - McKellar, Kenneth D., 1930s (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Misc. photographs of Congress, 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Includes Richard M. Nixon, Roman L. Hruska, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Everett M. Dirksen, Spiro T. Agnew, Hubert H. Humphrey, Strom Thurmon, Hiram L. Fong, Robert J. Dole, Gerald R. Ford, Hugh D. Scott, Charles E. Goodell, Karl E. Mundt, Thomas H. Kuchel, Leverett Saltonstall, Margaret Chase Smith, Carl T. Curtis; (1 of 2)
    - Misc. photographs of Congress, 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Includes Roman L. Hruska, Henry M. Jackson, Gerald R. Ford, Bourke B. Hickenlooper, Milton R. Young, George D. Aiken, Robert C. Byrd, Hiram L. Fong;(2 of 2)
    - Murphy, George L., 1970s (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Includes photograph of George L. Murphy and Arthur E. Scott; color portrait
    - Pepper, Claude D., 1930s (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Percy, Chares H., 1970s (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Photograph Album, 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Includes Hiram L. Fong, Everett M. Dirksen, and Barry M. Goldwater
    - Photograph Album, 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Photographs for Senate Historian, 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 6)
      From box labeled "Photos for Senate Historian"; includes Robert J. Dole, Hugh D. Scott, Jr.
    - Pittman, Key, 1930s (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Portraits of Republican Senators, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 8)
      (1 of 3); includes Everett M. Dirksen and Hiram L. Fong
    - Portraits of Republican Senators, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 9)
      (2 of 3); includes Barry M. Goldwater, Jacob K. Javits, Kenneth Keating, Bourke B. Hickenlooper, Roman L. Hruska
    - Portraits of Republican Senators, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 10)
      (3 of 3)
    - Roth, William V., Jr., 1970s (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Scott, Hugh D., Jr., 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Scott, William L., 1970s (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Senators 1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Senators 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Senators 1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Senators, 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Senators, 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Smith, Ellison D., 1930s-1940 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Smith, Margaret Chase, 1949-1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Stewart, Arthur T., 1930s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Thurmond, Strom, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Tower, John G., 1960s (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Adams, Alva B., 1920s-1940s (Box 12)
      4 negatives
    - Aiken, George D., 1956-1963 (Box 12)
      46 negatives
    - Allott, Gordon L., 1956-1953 (Box 12)
      150 negatives
    - Andrews, Charles O., 1935-1936 (Box 12)
      6 negatives
    - Ashurst, Henry F., 1930s (Box 12)
      11 negatives
    - Austin, Warren R., 1933-1940 (Box 12)
    - Ball, Joseph H., 1940-1949 (Box 12)
      3 negatives
    - Barbour, William W., 1931-1943 (Box 12)
    - Barkley, Alben W., 1940s-1950s (Box 12)
      25 negatives; includes Alben W. Barkley as Vice President
    - Bartlett, Edward L. (Bob), 1964-1966 (Box 12)
    - Bass, Ross, January 15, 1965 (Box 12)
      1 negative
    - Beall, John G., 1957-1963 (Box 12)
      70 negatives
    - Bender, George H., 1955-1956 (Box 12)
      10 negatives
    - Bennett, Wallace F., 1956-1963 (Box 12)
    - Berry, George L., 1937-1938 (Box 12)
      2 negatives
    - Bible, Alan H., 1957-1965 (Box 13)
      25 negatives
    - Bilbo, Theodore G., 1935-1948 (Box 13)
    - Black, Hugo L., 1927-1937 (Box 13)
    - Boggs, James C., 1961-1963 (Box 13)
    - Bone, Homer T., 1933-1934 (Box 13)
    - Borah, William E., 1920s-1930s (Box 13)
      15 negatives
    - Bridges, Henry Styles (Styles), 1936-1960 (Box 13)
      125 negatives
    - Brewster, Daniel B., August 13, 1964 (Box 13)
      7 negatives
    - Brooke, Edward W., III, August 23, 1966 (Box 13)
    - Brooks, Charles W., 1940s (Box 13)
    - Buckley, James L., 1971-1976 (Box 13)
    - Bulow, William J., 1931-1943 (Box 13)
    - Burke, Edward R., 1933-1940 (Box 13)
    - Bush, Prescott S., 1955-1961 (Box 13)
      40 negatives
    - Butler, John M., 1951-1962 (Box 13)
    - Byrd, Robert C., 1962-1964 (Box 13)
    - Byrd, Harry F., 1960s (Box 13)
    - Cannon, Howard W., 1960-1962 (Box 13)
    - Capehart, Homer E., 1960s (Box 13)
    - Capper, Arthur, 1930s-1940s (Box 13)
    - Caraway, Hattie Wyatt, 1931-1945 (Box 13)
      8 negatives
    - Carlson, Frank, 1963 (Box 13)
      30 negatives
    - Case, Francis H., 1950s (Box 13)
    - Case, Clifford P., 1955-1961 (Box 13)
    - Chandler, Albert B. (Happy), 1940s (Box 14)
    - Chapman, Virgil M., 1951 (Box 14)
      1 negative; car crash
    - Chavez, Dennis, 1959-1961 (Box 14)
    - Clark, Joel B., 1933-1945 (Box 14)
    - Connally, Thomas T. (Tom), 1930s-1950s (Box 14)
    - Cook, Marlow W., 1973 (Box 14)
    - Cooper, John S., 1945-1963 (Box 14)
    - Copeland, Royal S., 1930s (Box 14)
      3 negatives; with autogyro
    - Cotton, Norris H., 1955-1963 (Box 14)
    - Curtis, Carl T., 1950s-1970s (Box 14)
      50 negatives
    - Davis, James J., 1930-1945 (Box 14)
      9 negatives
    - Dirksen, Everett M., 1956-1963 (Box 14)
      35 negatives; several pictures with Dwight D. Eisenhower
    - Dodd, Thomas J., May 23, 1963 (Box 14)
    - Dole, Robert J., 1970s (Box 14)
    - Dominick, Peter H., 1963 (Box 14)
    - Donahey, Alvin V., 1935-1941 (Box 14)
    - Douglas, Paul H., 1966 (Box 14)
    - Downey, Sheridan, 1940s (Box 14)
    - Doxey, Wall, 1941-1943 (Box 14)
    - Duffy, Francis R., 1933-1939 (Box 14)
    - Eastland, James O., 1960s (Box 14)
      5 negatives
    - Ellender, Allen J., 1940s-1950s (Box 14)
    - Fannin, Paul J., 1967 (Box 14)
    - Fong, Hiram, 1959-1963 (Box 15)
      90 negatives, includes swearing in
    - Frazier, Lynn J., 1923-1941 (Box 15)
    - Frear, J. Allen, Jr., 1950s (Box 15)
    - Fulbright, J. William, 1960s (Box 15)
    - George, Walter F., 1940s (Box 15)
    - Gibson, Ernest W., Jr., 1940-1941 (Box 15)
    - Gillette, Guy M., 1940s (Box 15)
    - Glass, Carter, 1930s-1940s (Box 15)
    - Goldwater, Barry M., 1927-1963 (Box 15)
      175 negatives
    - Graves, Dixie B., 1950s (Box 15)
      2 negatives; as former senator
    - Green, Theodore F., 1950s (Box 15)
    - Griffin, Robert P., 1966-1970 (Box 15)
      9 negatives; includes color portrait
    - Gore, Albert A., 1953-1971 (Box 15)
    - Guffey, Joseph F., 1935-1947 (Box 15)
    - Gurney, Edward J., 1970 (Box 15)
      1 negative, portrait
    - Gurney, John C.(Chan), 1939-1951 (Box 15)